ecademy.com 2013-01-15

# Privacy Policy - Ecademy

**THE ECADEMY®**   
**PRIVACY POLICY**

**STATEMENT OF PRIVACY**  
Because your privacy is important to us, Ecademy operates by these principles:

(1) We collect and process "personal data" - as defined in the Data Protection Act 1998 - in providing Ecademy services. In particular, we use your Personal Information to better understand your requirements of your membership to The Ecademy, and we may occasionally inform you of new features, services and products from The Ecademy unless you opt-out of such notices. You can control the use of your data using "account settings"

(2) All personal data are processed by The Ecademy in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. Part of our compliance is the registration of the purposes for which we process data with the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO). This is available on the Public Register of Data Controllers at [www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/).

(3) You MUST be 16 years old or over to join the Ecademy website and/or attend Ecademy events.

(4) Any "sensitive personal data" - as defined in the legislation- will only be processed with your explicit consent - for example, racial or ethnic origin.

(5) The Ecademy has an obligation under the Act to ensure all data processed are correct and current, but we ask that you review and update your personal information at any time.

(6) By its very nature and purpose, the Ecademy website is a medium by which Business professional people seek to make contact with each other. Other members may contact you via the Ecademy forums, the private messaging system, via export contact tools, via mass mailing newsletter tools or directly to your e-mail addresses if visible on your profile. You can choose to stop receiving private messages and messages sent via the mass mail tools at anytime. All the personal information you enter onto the Ecademy site and choose to be displayed, will be viewable by any other member, by members who may export and save this data, or any casual visitor to the site, including search engines that index the pages of the Ecademy website. We cannot accept responsibility or liability for any processing conducted outside the remit of our services.

(7) During your Ecademy membership registration process, or at any time thereafter, you control which of the data you have provided is visible via the Privacy and Display settings when logged in at [http://www.ecademy.com/account.php?op=edit&type=privacy](http://www.ecademy.com/account.php?op=edit&type=privacy) and by choosing not to provide this information where this information is optional. Links and content about you created by other members, may be indexed and visible outside Ecademy based on their privacy settings.

(8) The Ecademy uses cookies or other similar software to collect data about users to track their movements around its website and in order to assist those users to automatically and effortlessly log in on subsequent visits to its site.

(9) Subscribers are able to see who within the membership has looked at their profile page. Advertisers within the EcademyAds Directory and Marketplace Listings are able to see who within the membership has looked at their web page, Club moderators are able to see who within the membership has looked at their club home page, you may amend your setting in your profile so you will not appear within these features, the default setting is on (you will appear).

(10) Data are only shared with third parties as part of our services and/or if we are required to do so by UK law. All data are subject to the UK Data Protection Act 1998 as this is where collection and storage occurs, although it may be accessed globally. We cannot accept liability for any processing conducted by third parties outside our remit.

(11) We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including personal information such as your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Some of our adverts are served by Google. Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on the Ecademy website. Google's use of a cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to Ecademy and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of this cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

None of the above affects your rights of access to any data we hold about you. If you wish to request a copy of these data, please email [webmaster@ecademy.com](mailto:webmaster@ecademy.com). Please note that any such request may attract an administration fee of £10.00, payable in advance and non-refundable.
